[QIFREY] There are
many kinds of magic,
but some are
of particular importance.
Four, to be precise.
Granting control
over that nourishing force
that sustains all life...
the Sigil of Water.
Turning stone to sand
and sand to stone,
enabling transformation
and movement...
the Sigil of Earth.
Making travel
to distant realms a reality,
through which so much progress
has been achieved...
the Sigil of Levitation.
And finally,
no less than humanity's
very sword and shield...
the Sigil of Flame.
Witches hold these four sigils
to be their foundation,
the Primary Tetrad.
- [Coco gasps]
- [QIFREY] So, then...
shall we give them a try?
[brushbuddy snores squeakily]
[scribbling]
[Tetia groans]
[Coco grunts softly]
[Tetia sighs]
Hmm.
[Coco yelps]
No, no, no!
What do I do now? Help!
[Coco exclaims]
[Coco groans]
There. Are you all right?
[COCO]
Thank you for that, Tetia.
[Tetia chuckles]
Thank you for your thanks!
What were you trying to do, anyway?
Practice my levitation magic
by drawing the Pyreball spell.
Word of warning.
The Sigil of Fire deals
with formless phenomena
and becomes dangerous
when out of balance,
so be sure to take care.
[COCO] I will.
[TETIA] Hm?
I thought you already mastered
levitation magic
at the Dadah Range.
Why do you still need
to practice it?
You were out there whoosh-whoosh
whooshing around, right?
Whoosh-whoosh-whoosh...
I suppose...
But I ruined the Sylph Shoes
Agott let me borrow.
I couldn't return them
to her like that.
I've restored everything
but the Casting Seal
on the soles.
The lines I draw
keep coming out wobbly.
[QIFREY] Perhaps...
this pen isn't right for you.
I merely picked it
from my own at random.
There may be another
that better suits you,
in terms of weight and grip.
Yes, of course.
On reflection, I think it's time
you chose one for yourself.
[Coco gasps]
[Tetia gasps, giggles]
Next stop, magic stationer's!
Stationer's?
Yes, they carry all manner
of magical goods.
Pens and ink and the like.
[COCO]
So they sell art supplies?
Magical art supplies.
[gasps] It sounds so wonderful!
If I'm dreaming,
please don't wake me!
Ah, Coco?
[COCO] This is all
so much to take in.
I think I need to lie down.
[brushbuddy squeaks]
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[wind blowing]
♪
[Coco exclaims]
[QIFREY] That island
on the sandbar is Kalhn...
...Township of the Marshwoods.
It's the closest witches' town
to our atelier.
[Coco exclaims]
- [girl laughs]
- [BOY] Wait for me!
A Casting Seal that makes
your skirt fuller!
I was afraid
the ink wasn't compatible.
[COCO]
Look at all these witches.
Would you care to learn
about the city's history?
For protection from
the molewyrms
on the far bank
of the Marshwoods,
the witches built part
of the sandbar into an island
that could support a watchtower.
Then, as more witches
gathered here,
it became an atelier town,
- and to this day...
- Uh, Master Qifrey?
- She's not listening.
- [AGOTT] Excuse me.
Thrilling as it would be
to play tour guide for Coco,
I have better things to do.
And shops I'd like to visit.
I'm going off on my own.
We'll meet you
at the magic stationer's!
[Coco sighs]
[QIFREY] So,
how are things going
with you and Agott?
[COCO] I'm not sure, but...
I hope we can be friends
someday.
[Coco exclaims]
- [TETIA] Coco! Over here!
- [Coco gasps]
Don't get left behind!
Wow.
[Coco chuckles softly]
Incredible.
It's like a dream.
Uh?
[Coco exclaims]
[Coco gasps softly]
[TETIA] Coco!
We're not supposed
to get separated!
[TETIA] Kalhn's full of people,
isn't it?
[RICHEH] Too many.
It makes me tired.
The magic stationer's.
It's called the Starry Sword.
[Coco gasps softly]
[door creaks]
[birds chirping]
[Coco gasps softly]
[footsteps]
[birds chirping]
There's a tree growing through
the middle of the shop.
[MAN] My, my!
Now this is surprising.
A witch's apprentice gawking
at a Silverwood Tree.
Are you unfamiliar
with something so elementary?
None of that.
Coco here is still
a relatively new apprentice.
Oh! Coco, you say?
So, she's the one.
Well, now,
that clears things up!
Sorry, wee one!
Of course you wouldn't know it.
Suppose all's fair.
I didn't recognize you either.
Seems we're even! [laughs]
That's Mr. Nolnoa!
He's the owner
of the Starry Sword!
That I am!
With the help
of my grandson Tartah,
I made all the components
you see in this establishment.
All the pens, all the ink,
all of it! No exceptions!
I can also extract ink
at any concentration.
Extract it?
[clears throat]
Yes, why don't I show you,
Coco, wasn't it?
Come along, now.
Yes, sir!
[snipping]
[Coco gasps softly]
[COCO] Uh?
[birds chirping]
[NOLNOA] Hmm.
- [Coco gasps softly]
- [Tetia chuckles softly]
- [brushbuddy squeals]
- It turned black!
That is called Woodcruor.
Its branches are silvery white
when alive and healthy,
but quickly turn black
upon their death.
In that state,
it becomes toxic,
both to humans
and to the tree itself.
And yet,
through a simple process
of dissolving it in water
and then straining out
the excess...
we have a crude Conjuring Ink,
no less than
- the very source of all magic.
- [Coco gasps softly]
Regular ink is made
from the soot that's produced
when you burn normal wood.
But Conjuring Ink...
that's different.
It's made
from the tree's "cruor."
Literally, its blood.
As I'm sure you can imagine,
the Silverwood is an extremely
important tree to witches.
I should say!
Why, they're the only tree
from which the ink
can be extracted.
It sounds amazing!
- Precious, too.
- Both true!
There's even
an old legend about it!
[NOLNOA] As the story goes,
a long time ago,
there was a Silverwood tree
that fell in love with a witch!
It offered its branches
as wands,
- and its blood as ink.
- Wands?
Uh? [laughs]
Is that why
you're here today?
- To buy a wand?
- Yes!
[Nolnoa chuckles]
[Nolnoa humming]
Ah...
Well, then...
go on and try a few out.
You'll need this, of course.
I'm sure you
and the perfect wand
will find each other.
[Coco gasps]
[footsteps]
[TETIA] Have any idea
what you want?
I really like lighter wands,
if you want my opinion!
[COCO] Which should I try first?
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] Hold on! Come back!
[Tetia pants]
Coco, wait!
- Oh! What do we do?
- [brushbuddy squeaks softly]
[RICHEH] I don't know.
But if she wanders off
on her own, she'll get lost.
[TETIA] We have
to catch up with her!
[running footsteps]
[grunts] Hey!
[Coco panting]
[TETIA] Agott! [panting]
[AGOTT] Tetia,
what's going on? Hm?
[TETIA] Just come with us!
Hurry!
[AGOTT] What? Hold on!
[grunts] What is this about?
[Coco panting]
[♪ intense music playing]
[Coco gasps]
[Coco panting]
[AGOTT] Coco, stop running!
[TETIA] Wait for us, Coco!
[brushbuddy squeaks softly]
[brushbuddy squeaks]
♪
Explain yourself, now!
Where are you going, anyway?
There was a witch
outside the shop!
The same one who gave me
the forbidden magic book!
See for yourself, they're...
They're, um...
What a waste of precious energy.
Oh, well, at least we're
all together again, right?
Now! Back to the shop!
[RICHEH] That's odd.
We only went
one alley down, right?
But it's so different.
And the brushbuddy's gone.
Huh... Good point.
These surroundings
are nothing like before.
The walls and floors
are made of a white stone
you don't see in Kalhn.
Which means,
that this isn't Kalhn.
[TETIA] But how can that be?
We didn't pass through
a Windowway,
and it's not like
we could just teleport!
Wait here.
I'll take a look from above!
[AGOTT] Tetia may have stumbled
on the right answer.
[BOTH] Huh?
We could, in fact,
have been directly teleported
without being aware of it.
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] No. Spells like that
aren't allowed, are they?
That kind of magic is...
Forbidden.
[Tetia screams]
Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh, no!
This is definitely not Kalhn!
We need to get out of here!
[AGOTT] Wait. Come back!
What's the matter with you?
Tetia, calm down!
Just tell us what you saw!
Don't worry about what I saw,
worry about what saw me!
[WITCH] I have no business
with the others,
but, oh, well...
[all gasp]
[footsteps thudding]
[dragon growls]
[WITCH] Coco, I bid you welcome
to the world of magic.
[dragon roars]
[WITCH] You are our
one and only hope.
[birds chirping]
[QIFREY] Mr. Nolnoa,
have you seen my apprentices?
Not in a while.
Perhaps they got bored
and went for a walk.
What? That's impossible!
How could anyone
get bored in your shop?
Why, I could browse this place
all day!
Flattery will get you
nowhere, son.
Something's wrong.
My students
aren't the sort of girls
who would have run off
without thanking you.
- But where could they be?
- [footsteps]
[TARTAH] I can tell you.
I saw them chasing after
a strangely dressed witch
a while ago.
A witch wearing a mask
that looked like an eyeball.
[wind blowing]
[low growl]
[Tetia whimpers]
[Coco gasps softly]
[AGOTT] Careful now.
Maintain eye contact,
and start backing up slowly.
Once we're far enough,
I'll give the word and we'll run
with all our might.
[Coco gasps]
[dragon growling]
[AGOTT] Slowly...
slowly.
[dragon growling]
[AGOTT] Now!
[dragon roars]
[dragon groans]
This is it! Let's move!
[all panting]
Agott, that was absolutely
incredible!
Was it a fire spell?
It used the Fire Sigil
and the Sign of Spiraling Wind.
And you drew it that fast
just now?
Of course not!
You prepare mostly drawn spells
in your Palm Quire.
That way, all you have to do
is close the ring
and you can use them
in a moment!
[Coco squeals] You're amazing!
Will you show me
how to draw that later?
Do you even understand
how much danger we're in?
[TETIA] Agott!
It's a dead end!
We can't go any farther!
Should we try another path?
- [thudding]
- [all gasp]
[TETIA] What do we do?
The dragon's going to find us,
and gobble us up.
[dragon growls]
I don't want to die here.
I haven't left a single spell
for the world to remember me by!
Why did I have to
get dragged in...
[Coco gasps]
[Tetia gasps]
[AGOTT] Tetia, calm down.
We're witch apprentices, remember?
Our magic will save us.
[Tetia breathes shakily]
I'll use a Wall Breaker spell
to create an escape hatch
for us.
Richeh, Tetia, buy some time.
- [TETIA] Right.
- [RICHEH] Understood.
[TETIA] There.
[AGOTT] Where should I draw it?
[RICHEH] Around here, maybe.
[TETIA] Add the signs
to this sigil.
Agott, come take a look!
[COCO] She didn't say it,
but I saw in her eyes
that she blames me for this.
[AGOTT] You're right.
This should do the trick nicely.
[COCO] And she's right,
it's all my fault.
Come on.
Fly away!
[dragon growling]
That should keep it busy
for a little while.
Well done, really.
[RICHEH] Nice work.
Amazing. All of them.
[Coco gasps]
[gasps] Is that...
Agott, look up there!
There's a...
- [Agott grunting]
- [COCO] Oh, no!
What were you thinking?
Never touch a witch
while she's drawing!
I'm sorry! I didn't mean to...
Oh, well, that's good to hear!
You didn't mean to.
You didn't mean
to turn your mother to stone!
And you didn't mean
to put us all in danger.
It's one accident
after another, isn't it?
But that doesn't mean
it's not your fault!
At least get it
through your head
how ignorant you are,
and stop trying to do anything!
Um... What now?
[AGOTT]
There's no time to start over.
We'll just have to go back
and find another way...
[RICHEH] Done.
Excellent. You saved us, Richeh.
Now let's put this
dead end behind us.
I meant this part of the maze.
However, that doesn't mean
other interpretations
are invalid.
[Tetia gasps softly]
[AGOTT] Tetia.
[Coco breathes shakily]
[COCO] Master Qifrey, I'm lost.
What should I do?
[wind blowing]
[NOLNOA] Qifrey!
Any sign of the girls yet?
[QIFREY] No, they're not outside
anywhere nearby.
I didn't expect this.
The Brimmed Caps
making direct contact
portends grave danger.
[COCO] Hold on! [pants]
That was a Brimmed Cap?
My word.
To think one of them
would come here!
[QIFREY]
A dangerous faction of witches
clad in hats
from a bygone era,
their faces hidden
behind masks.
I'd hoped Coco might
eventually lead us to them.
I never imagined
they'd come to her.
Tartah, do you remember
anything else?
Please think!
Well, um...
I'm sorry, but not really, no.
- It's all right.
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
[QIFREY] Uh?
You...
You're the brushbuddy
Coco brought back.
- Were you with them?
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
Where are they?
[brushbuddy squeaks]
[indistinct chatter]
[Qifrey panting]
[QIFREY]
It'll be getting dark soon.
Please, everyone...
be safe!
[♪ closing theme song playing]